CHIN HUI CHEW

• chinhuic@gmail.com • (857) 753 - 8511

SUMMARY

Experienced in defining, building, and scaling products from the ground up at Microsoft and Uber, with a track record of getting things done and delivering real impact. Current work focuses on machine learning and natural language processing (NLP).

WORK EXPERIENCE

MICROSOFT, COMMUNICATIONS INTELLIGENCE

Bellevue, WA, US

February 2018 – Present

- Senior Applied Scientist
- Leading a team to develop new AI-based features on Outlook to help users triage their emails more efficiently
 Developed and evaluated state-of-the-art NLP models to predict email reply actions
- Improved current model in production by incorporating personalized action-based features
- Shipped the first user productivity-oriented metric for Outlook: the metric is a key shipping criterion for Focused Inbox classification experiments and new Outlook UX
- Drove collaborations with teams across functions and regions on rolling out new experiences. Collaborations include initiating
 functional testing, orchestrating offline data pipelines, deploying models to production, and metrics reporting
- Designed and implemented pipeline to analyze customer feedback on incorrect classifications of important emails, saving hundreds of hours per year

MICROSOFT, COMMUNICATIONS INTELLIGENCE

Bellevue, WA, US

Applied Scientist Intern

May 2017 – August 2017

- Built a logistic regression model to predict important emails: insights contributed to product directions of Focused Inbox
- Processed petabytes of user data and feature-engineered over 60 predictors based on user actions, sender-recipient relationships, and historical data: newly engineered features contributed to improvement in prediction effectiveness

UBER

Singapore

Operations Associate

July 2015 – July 2016

- Designed and executed A/B tests to increase engagement among riders and driver-partners, with at least 3 experiments yielding statistically significant results and increasing targeted ridership by almost 150%
- Influenced senior management to introduce mobile push and SMS notifications for Singapore riders as additional marketing
 channels by building a predictive model on expected response rate. Riders receiving SMS were twice as likely to take a trip
- Created driver incentives with weekly budget of over S\$100k and presented results in weekly citywide and regional meetings
- Constructed and scaled operations processes for Uber's car rental subsidiary, which grew 300%

BNP PARIBAS

Singapore

Regulatory Compliance Analyst

August 2014 – June 2015

- Investigated escalated alerts to prevent money laundering and criminal action, preventing \$\$200k in fraudulent transactions
- Automated trade monitoring by integrating Bloomberg and Excel, resulting in efficiency gains of 250 person-hours per year

PROJECTS

Various Competitions

KAGGLE

Bellevue, WA, US

July 2019 - Present

- Ranked among top 5% of worldwide Kaggle users in Competitions category (Expert status)
- Attained top 7% in APTOS 2019 Blindness Detection with a CNN-based model to detect diabetic retinopathy
- Achieved top 6% in RSNA Intracranial Hemorrhage Detection with an algorithm to detect hemorrhage and its subtypes

EDUCATION

HARVARD UNIVERSITY

Cambridge, MA, US

Master of Science in Computational Science and Engineering, GPA 3.92

August 2016 – December 2017

Coursework highlights: Machine Learning, Data Science, Systems Development, Numerical Methods, Statistical Inference

IMPERIAL COLLEGE LONDON

London, UK

Master and Bachelor in Biomedical Engineering, First Class Honors

October 2010 - June 2014

Awarded Centenary Prize in Bioengineering as best MEng student with overall grade of 83%